two solid brands set to go toe-to-toe in
a winner takes all battle royale fashion
all right that might be a little bit
dramatic but i do have two awesome pairs
of dumbbells to review for you guys
today i've got the classic rogue hex
dumbbells and the fully knurled rep
fitness dumbbells which one reigns
supreme
stick around and find out
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake and what
might as well be my second home at this
point the bar ben garage gym and for
today's review i've got a pair of rogue
fitness dumbbells and a pair of rep
fitness dumbbells in this video i'm
going to compare these two and help you
decide which one is best for you but
before we get started with any of that i
got to let you know we have reviewed a
ton of dumbbells on barbin.com you want
to learn more about our best list just
google far bend best dumbbells it's
gonna pull right up for you you can read
all about it find out which one takes
home our top spot
now let's get after it
[Music]
okay so let's kick this video off with
the similarities between these two
dumbbells as you can see they both have
that hexagonal shaped head which is
ideal for anything you're going to be
using them on the floor for as well as
you know if you drop them they're not
going to roll all the way across the
floor you'll have to run all over the
place going to get them they're both
coated in rubber meaning it's going to
be a low balance and it's going to
protect your floors in the long run as
well and the really cool thing here is
you can get a full set or you can get
individual pairs from both of these
brands
if you want to slowly build up and
create your full set
[Music]
okay so what about those differences
between these two dumbbells well
starting with the handles both companies
went about this in a different way so
rep fitness has a fully knurled handle
meaning from end to end
it's fully knurled with rogue you're
going to find the knurlings really only
in the middle and it also features an
ergonomic design meaning it's thicker in
the middle than it is on the ends
and with rep fitness you're going to
find that diameter to be the same all
the way across
speaking of diameter
with rogue you're going to find that the
10 pounds and less they're going to have
a diameter around 25 millimeters
anything 12 and a half and up is gonna
be 35 millimeters
with rep anything 20 pounds and under is
going to have a 28 millimeter diameter
and then anything above 20 pounds is
gonna have a 34 millimeter diameter you
might not notice the difference but it's
worth noting that and while both of
these knurlings are a little bit on the
medium side of things
i kind of feel as if rogue's knurling is
a bit more abrasive than rep fitness and
while
both of these dumbbells are a little bit
more expensive than some other brands
that are of lesser quality
there's also brands out there that are
about the same quality that are more
expensive so in reality both of these
fall about in the middle compared to the
rest of the market but when you compare
these two specifically rogue is actually
a little bit cheaper than rep fitness
with their individual pairs
the 25 pound pair you see here today
from rogue is going to run you about 90
while this 25 pound pair from rep
fitness it's about 130
okay so as i mentioned both of these
companies
charge a good amount especially compared
to a pair of dumbbells you could go get
from walmart or maybe from a brand of
lesser quality
but that's for good reason they're both
great
and it's also worth mentioning these are
still going to be cheaper than a pair of
urethane dumbbells
now
let's talk about comparison with
individual pairs
starting with rogue a two and a half
pound pair of dumbbells it's gonna run
you about 20 bucks this 25 pound pair
like i said it's about 90
and the 125 pound pair of dumbbells it's
about 450 bucks
i'm not gonna lie it's not necessarily
cheap
but they're still a little bit cheaper
than rep fitness so the two and a half
pound
pair from rep that's about 30 bucks this
25 pound pair right here it's about 130
and the 125 pound pair that's like 540
bucks
[Music]
okay so let's compare the full sets now
with both of these brands starting with
rogue the 5 to 50 pound set it's gonna
run you about a thousand dollars the 55
to 100 pound set that's about nine
hundred dollars in that 105 to 125 pound
set that's about twenty two hundred
dollars now they don't offer as many
options as well compared to rep so if
you wanted you know a five to one
hundred pound set of dumbbells well
you're gonna have to purchase that 5 to
and the 55 to 100 pound set which is
gonna make you spend more money in the
long run
so with rep you can get that five to
fifty pound set about eleven hundred
dollars
the 5 to 75 pound set about 2 200
the 5 to 100 pound set i mentioned it's
gonna cost you about thirty six hundred
dollars the 55 75 pound set that's about
1250 and that 80 to 100 pound set that's
gonna run you about fifteen hundred
dollars okay so since both of these
dumbbells are of similar quality we're
talking about price here specifically
rep gets the edge if you're a little
tight on money and just dying to get a
five to a hundred pound set as i said
that 500 pound set from rep it's about 3
and with rogue you don't even have that
opportunity you got to get the 5 to 50
pound and the 55 to 100 pound set that's
going to make you spend about 300 more
and that money could be used for a nice
storage rack for your dumbbells but at
the same time if you're super particular
about your dumbbells and you just love
the ergonomically shaped handles that
rogue offers
then you might be fine spending a little
bit more money
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
that went into the rogue dumbbells as i
mentioned anything 10 pounds and less is
going to have a diameter on the handles
of 25 millimeters once you hit 12 and a
half pounds and up well the diameter is
going to jump up to 35 millimeters on
the handles the handles are
ergonomically shaped meaning they're
thicker in the middle than they are at
the ends they're chrome plated and they
have a little bit of a medium knurling
on here which really makes you get that
good grip during your lifts
and once again i couldn't help but
notice these are a little bit more
abrasive than the rep fitness knurling
but that might not be too much of a
cause for concern
the hexagon shape here is great for any
floor usage and plus if you drop them
they're not going to roll away from you
all over your gym
now as far as how the heads and the
handles were constructed
rogue has it listed on their website as
a proprietary head to handle
construction
what does that mean
honestly i don't know i reached out to
the customer support team tried to get
some more clarity on that for you guys
they weren't able to give me a good
answer
but
you know this is from rogue rogue is
known for their high quality equipment
and really it's no different in these
dumbbells right here they feel really
sturdy in my hands
and if i drop them i'm not afraid of the
heads just popping off of them
now let's dig into some more of the
details here with these rogue dumbbells
the really cool thing is that you know
if you don't want to spend all that
money up front on a full set you can get
them in individual pairs and then over
time add on and get that full set that
you're looking for the handles once
again they're ergonomically shaped make
sure you do grab them in the middle
because that's where the knurling is
located that's the thickest point of
contact for your hands that's going to
give you the best available grip
and while the numbers they're the same
color as the rest of the head as you can
see
but they do kind of pop out at you still
because there is a little bit of a lip
which allows you to easily see which
dumbo you're going to grab without any
hesitation okay so now let's talk about
the rep fitness dumbbells and the build
that went behind constructing these all
right so like i said anything from 5 to
20 pounds you're going to notice a
handle diameter of 28 millimeters
anything after that 34 millimeters a
little bit different than rogue but you
might not notice too much of a
difference in your own personal
experience with it so the handles here
are also fully knurled meaning from head
to head it's that fully knurled pattern
which really i think can give you a
better overall grip no matter where you
grab it
the heads are also attached via friction
welding okay now what does that mean
well basically what they did was they
spun the head and the handle against
each other at such a fast rate they
fused together so
these things are not going to fall off
it's basically one big piece you're good
to go
so some more details now of these rep
dumbbells they're also available in
individual pairs or full set so once
again if you don't want to spend all
that money up front you can get
individual pairs over time and create
that full set that you're looking for
the handles are not ergonomically shaped
here
so
they're the same diameter all the way
across but they are fully knurled
the low odor rubber coating on these
dumbbells basically makes it so where
they're good to go as soon as you open
them out of the box
now
i didn't notice too big of a difference
between the rogue and the rep fitness
dumbbells when unboxing them but i could
tell a little bit of a smell with rogue
and with rep fitness really didn't smell
much at all but it's not that big of a
difference
the numbers on the rep fitness dumbbells
don't necessarily pop out as much at you
as the rogue ones do but you can still
easily see which dumbbell is which and
go grab one without any hesitation
all right so which brand should you buy
then well really it boils down to
personal preference
so for me
i really like the fully knurled handles
on the rip fitness dumbbells and don't
really care so much for the ergonomic
handles from rogue which makes me lean
more towards reps hex dumbbells and i'm
also a bit of a penny pitcher so
i'm going to try to go and do the most
cost efficient thing which is to go and
get a full set with rep fitness i'm
going to save about 300
if i go for the 500 pound set than what
i would with rogue since i have to do
the 5 to 50 and the 55 to 100 pound set
with that money i can go and get a nice
storage rack for my dumbbells some other
gym equipment maybe even take my
girlfriend out for that nice date that
she deserves
[Music]
at the end of the day you can't really
go wrong with either one of these
dumbbells you know me personally i'm
just looking to save as much money as
possible and with rep fitness i'm able
to do that but at the same time
if you do like the ergonomically shaped
handles that rogue offers you know you
get that extra millimeter of thickness
especially for those heavier lifts or
maybe you just have a soft spot for
rogue then yeah maybe these are the
dumbbells for you
they're still great quality i just
prefer the handles from rep and i'm able
to save a few bucks
[Music]
well that concludes today's match-up of
the rogue dumbbells
versus the rep fitness dumbbells these
are both awesome options to consider
when looking to fill out your home gym
i personally love the fully knurled
handle from rep fitness and that's what
i'm going to have to go with here today
the rogue dumbbells are very good
quality they're very durable but i
simply cannot pass up this fully knurled
handle and when i'm going to buy a full
set i'm trying to save a little bit of
money thanks for watching everybody i
hope this video helped you guys out
helped you decide which dumbbells to go
with which ones are a better fit for you
as always stay on the lookout for my
next video and in the meantime search
barbin
rogue dumbbells first rep dumbbells and
you can read over everything we discuss
here today
now go get your workout in i'll see you
later
[Music]
you